breathehr.com 2016-12-25

# Privacy Policy & Cookies

## WHO THIS POLICY APPLIES TO

Your privacy is important to us.  We comply with the UK Data Protection Act 1988 as may be amended (“Data Protection Law”). This Privacy Policy tells you what to expect when we collect personal information.  It applies to personal information we collect about:

  * People who visit and use our Site
  * Subscribers to breatheHR Services
  * People who contact us
  * Job applicants and our current and former employees.

## HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION

We process and use personal information in a number of different ways depending on who has provided the information and for what purposes.

### People who visit and use our Site

 **Signing up to newsletters, email updates, requesting demos and other interactive feature** s

Our Site may invite you to sign up for certain features, such as newsletters, email updates, demo requests and other general interactive features.  Where you provide information for these purposes, we will use your information to provide the relevant service or feature that you have requested and to manage your preferences.  We may also gather statistics around email opening and clicks using industry standard technologies to help us monitor and improve our newsletters and email subscriptions.  You will have the ability to unsubscribe from any repeat communications at any time.

 **Site analytics**

When someone visits www.breathehr.com we use third party services, such as Google Analytics, to collect standard internet log information and details of visitor behaviour patterns.  We do this to find out things such as the number of visitors to the various parts of the Site. This information is only processed in a way which does not identify anyone. We do not make, and do not allow our third party service provider to make, any attempt to find out the identities of those visiting our Site. If we do want to collect personally identifiable information through our Site, we will be open and clear about this. We will make it clear when we collect personal information and will explain what we intend to do with it.

 **Use of cookies by breatheHR**

Our Site uses cookies.  Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the site.  We also use them to allow us to recognise you and your preferred settings.  We may use a temporary ’session cookie’ in order to perform the secure login to our website. This cookie contains no personal information, just a long random number, and is deleted from your web browser when you exit the Site.  Temporary cookies may be used in the transactional part of the Site to authenticate you as an authorised User after you have logged in.

Most web browsers allow some control of most cookies through the browser settings.  To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, visit www.aboutcookies.org or www.allaboutcookies.org.

To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

If you disable cookies on our Site, some features of the Site may not be available to you.

 **Site search engine**

If you perform any searches on our Site, search queries and results may be logged anonymously to help us to improve our Site and search functionality.  No user-specific data is collected.

 **Blog**

We may also collect information about visitors’ activities on our blog, for example the number of users viewing a page on the blog, to monitor and report on the effectiveness of the blog and help us improve it.  Visitors may be required to enter a name and email address to view our blog and/or post comments.

 **Security and performance**

We may use third parties to help maintain the security and performance of our Site.  To deliver this service we may need to allow the third party to process the IP addresses of Site visitors.

### Subscribers to breatheHR Services

In addition to the above, where you subscribe to use our Services, we will need to use some personal information in the context of our relationship pursuant to the [EULA](https://app.breathehr.com/content/terms_and_conditions).

 **Application process**

When you apply to subscribe to use our Services, the information you give us may contain some personal information, for example where the business is a sole trader and or contact details of a relevant member of staff.  We will use this for its own purposes to assess your application and provide our Services to you as applicable.

 **Subscribing to breatheHR**

Our subscription Services are provided according to our [EULA](https://app.breathehr.com/content/terms_and_conditions) and contain features which enable Users to upload, store and process substantial amounts of personal information, for example HR files for your business, some of which may be sensitive personal information.  When you provide any personal information to us in the course of using our subscription Services, you do so as the “data controller” under UK Data Protection Law. We shall only process it in accordance with the [EULA](https://app.breathehr.com/content/terms_and_conditions) in the context of providing the Services to you and do so as “data processor”.  You and we shall both comply with prevailing UK data protection legislation at all times in this regard.

### People who contact us

We may record personal information provided to us by telephone, email, in person or otherwise in writing or electronically.  We will only use your information for the purposes that you provided it to us and for administrative purposes, always in compliance with Data Protection Law.  Email monitoring or blocking software may be used.  Please be aware that you have a responsibility to ensure that any communications from you are within the bounds of the law.

 **Interactions on social media**

We may also interact with you on social media.  If you submit any information to us via social media facilities controlled by us (e.g. our Facebook page or Twitter feed), we shall deal with it according to this Privacy Policy.

### Job applicants, current and former employees

When individuals apply to work for us, we will only use the information they supply to us to process their application and to monitor recruitment statistics. Where we want to disclose information to a third party, for example where we want to take up a reference or obtain a ‘disclosure’ from the Criminal Records Bureau we will not do so without informing the applicant beforehand, unless the disclosure is required by law.

Personal information about unsuccessful candidates will be held for 12 months after the recruitment exercise has been completed, it will then be destroyed or deleted. We may retain de-personalised statistical information about applicants to help inform our recruitment activities, but no individuals are identifiable from that information.

Once a person has taken up employment with us, we will compile a file relating to their employment. The information contained in this will be kept secure and will only be used for purposes directly relevant to that person’s employment. Once their employment with us has ended, we will retain the file in accordance with the requirements of our retention schedule and then delete it.

## GENERAL

 **Third parties:** We contract with a number of third parties to assist us in providing our Site and Services.  For example, we may use third parties to develop our Site and to provide the servers on which our Site is hosted.  Wherever third parties are involved in processing personal information on our behalf, we shall ensure they do so in accordance with UK Data Protection Law.  Third parties are not allowed to use your personal information for their own purposes.

 **Server location:** Our Site servers are and will always be located in the UK and/or the EEA. In order to effectively process credit or debit card transactions it may be necessary for the bank or card processing agency to verify your personal information for authorisation with an entity outside the EEA. Such information will not be transferred out of the EEA for any other purpose.

 **Business reorganisation:  ** In addition to the above, we may transfer your personal information to a third party as part of a sale of some or all of our business and assets to any third party or as part of any business restructuring or reorganisation, in which event we will take steps to ensure that your privacy rights under this Privacy Policy continue to be protected.

 **Financial transactions:** Under no circumstances will we hold payment details such as your card number, expiry date and security code on our servers. Where payments are handled through an accredited payment bureau, you should visit their website to view their privacy policy.

 **Links to other websites:**   This privacy policy only covers our Site.  Any other websites which may be linked to by this Site will be subject to their own privacy policy, which may differ from ours and we are not responsible for the content provided on any third party web sites.

 **Changes to this Privacy Policy:  ** We keep our Privacy Policy under regular review.  Updates to it shall become effective when published on our Site.  This Privacy Policy was last updated on 6 May 2016.

 **Complaints or queries:  ** This Privacy Policy is drafted with brevity and clarity in mind.  It does not provide exhaustive detail of all aspects of our collection and use of personal information.  However, we will endeavour to provide additional information or explanation if needed.  Any requests for this should be sent to the address below.

 **Access to your personal information:** We try to be as open as we can be in terms of giving people access to their personal information. Individuals can find out if we hold any personal information by making a ‘subject access request’ under the Data Protection Act 1998. If we do hold information about you we will:

  * give you a description of it;
  * tell you why we are holding it;
  * tell you who it could be disclosed to; and
  * let you have a copy of the information in an intelligible form.

To make a request to us for any personal information we may hold you need to put the request in writing to the address provided below.

If we do hold information about you, you can ask us to correct any mistakes by writing to the address below.

## FURTHER INFORMATION

“We”, “us” or “our” refer to Centurion Management Systems Limited (trading as breatheHR).

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact:

Centurion Management Systems ltd t/as breatheHR, Unit 19 Oakhurst Business Park, Wilberforce Way, Southwater, West Sussex RH13 9RT.  [info@breatheHR.com](mailto:info@breatheHR.com) 01403 288700
